<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="topics">
        <item>Dice / Difficulty</item>
        <item>Chances</item>
        <item>Blessed / Cursed</item>
        <item>Mandy</item>
        <item>Skids</item>
        <item>Reroll Ones</item>
        <item>Add One</item>
        <item>Shotgun</item>
        <item>About</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="contents" formatted="false">
        <item>When performing any type of skill check in Arkham Horror, a roll of the dice is used to determine if the character passes or fails the check. In general, the Difficulty of a skill check is defined as the number of 5s or 6s (successes) that must be rolled to pass the check. Use the Dice slider to indicate exactly how many dice the character will be rolling for a given check. If the number of Dice being rolled is less than the Difficulty of the check (e.g. you have one die to get two successes), the probability you will pass is 0%. However, there is no single skill check which is guaranteed to pass 100% of the time; the highest possible probability for a single check is reported as >99.9%.</item>
        <item>There are situations in the game where it is possible to attempt a certain skill check more than one time. For example, combat can continue as long as your character is conscious; if your character is fighting a monster that deals one stamina damage per attack, and your character has three stamina, you have three chances to pass the combat check. The Chances slider indicates how many times a check can be attempted and calculates the probability that at least one of the attempts passes. Put another way, when the Chances slider is set to ‘n’, it calculates 1.0 subtracted by the probability that you will fail all ‘n’ chances for the same check.</item>
        <item>Blessings and Curses are statuses that your character can obtain throughout the game. When Blessed, a character can count 4s as a success during a skill check. When Cursed, a character cannot count 5s as a success during a skill check. By rule, a character cannot be Blessed and Cursed at the same time.</item>
        <item>Mandy Thompson is an investigator that has a unique ability not replicated by any other item or character in the game: once per turn, she can let any character reroll any of the failures from his/her skill check. This is a far more powerful ability than simply rerolling a skill check, since the character can keep all of the success dice rolled as part of the initial roll. For example, if a character has a check with two Difficulty and can only roll two Dice, and on the initial roll he rolls one success and one failure, Mandy’s ability lets the character reroll the one failure to attempt to get a second success. Note that if the Chances slider is used, after the first Chance, all subsequent Chance calculations ignore Mandy’s ability, since she can only use her ability once per turn.</item>
        <item>Skids O\'Toole is an investigator from the Innsmouth Horror expansion with the following ability: once per skill check, he is allowed to roll two additional dice for each 1 he originally rolls. For example, if Skids has a skill check with two Difficulty and he is only allowed to roll one Dice, if he rolls a 1, he is then able to use his ability and roll two additional Dice to attempt to get two successes. Note that if the Chances slider is used, after the first Chance, all subsequent Chance calculations ignore Skids\' ability, since it can only be used once per check.</item>
        <item>Certain skills allow your character to, once per skill check, reroll all dice showing a result of 1. These skills are Camouflage, Linguistics, Listen, Persuade, Run, and Wrestle, introduced in the Kingsport expansion; and Clairvoyant, introduced in the Miskatonic expansion. Note that if the Chances slider is used, after the first Chance, all subsequent Chance calculations ignore the Reroll Ones skill, since these skills can only be used once per check.</item>
        <item>Certain skills allow your character to add 1 to the value of each die rolled for a certain check. These skills, introduced in the Dunwich expansion, are Dodge, Grapple, Hide, Library Use, Psychology, and Spot Hidden. This skill can “stack” with a Blessing or Curse; for example, if you are both Blessed and have an Add One skill, then for the relevant skill check, all 3s, 4s, 5s, and 6s rolled will count as successes. A Curse and an Add One skill cancel each other out, and all other things equal, the “base calc” (Dice / Difficulty calc with no options turned on) is the same as the calc with both of these options turned on.</item>
        <item>The Shotgun is a weapon used during combat checks which counts each 6 rolled as two successes each. For example, during a combat check with the Shotgun, if the difficulty of the check is three, and you roll a 5 and a 6, you succeed at the check, since the 5 counts for one success and the 6 counts for two successes. Note that the Shotgun does not increase the probability of success if the Difficulty of the check is one, since rolling a 6 with or without the Shotgun will give you enough successes to succeed at the check. Also note that the Shotgun only considers “natural 6s” to be worth two successes; a check with both a Shotgun and an Add One skill counts a roll of 5 as one success, even though the value of the die has been incremented to 6 by the Add One skill.</item>
        <item>ArkhamCalc. Copyright &#169; 2014 Matthew Cole. This program is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either version 2 of the License, or (at your option) any later version. This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU General Public License for more details. Icon adapted from Arkahm Horror Dice Set.</item>
    </string-array>    
</resources>
